（ナルト）シカマル！　いるか？
Shikamaru, are you in here?
（シカナル）あん？　なんだよ？
What is it?
Ino needs you.
いのが　用があるって…。
何してんだ？
What are you doing?
写真の選別だよ。
選別？　なんで？
Sorting photos.
Sorting? What for?
These photos were salvaged
from the disaster area.
（シホ）被災地から
集められた写真なんです。
（シホ）大事な写真もあるだろうし→
I'm sure there are some
important photos here,
so we want to return them
to the owners.
持ち主が判明するものは
返そうと思って。
オメエも知ってる人がいたら
教えてくれよ。
Look through them and
see if you recognize anyone.
Sure! I can help with something like that.
あぁ　それくらいなら
俺でも手伝えそうだな。
と　いっても
知らない人ばっかだな…。
I don't know any of these people.
これは…。
This is...
I remembered something I've gotta do!
俺　用を思い出したってばよ！
えっ？
Huh?
I'm taking this photo.
あぁ…　この写真　もらってくぜ！
おい！　ナルト。
- Hey, Naruto!
- I'm taking this photo.
Oh, that's right.
あっ！　そうだ。　チューリップって
どっかに咲いてたかな？
Do you know if tulips are
in bloom anywhere around here?
チューリップですか？　ナルト君
ロマンチックな花が好きなんですね。
Tulips?
That's such a romantic flower, Naruto.
チューリップの花言葉って
永遠の愛なんですよ。
In flower language,
tulips mean "eternal love."
《なんか　面倒くせぇ視線が…》
I don't like that look she's giving me.
そんなら　里の東にある花畑なら
無事なんじゃないか？
I think the flower garden on
the east side of the village is still intact.
サンキューな　シカマル！
あぁ。
Thanks, Shikamaru!
Sure.
でも　アイツ　チューリップを
どうするつもりだ？
But why does he want tulips?
さぁ？
Who knows?
《永遠の愛か…》
Eternal love, huh?
((やべぇ！　降ってきたってばよ。
Shucks! It's starting to rain.
急いで帰んねえと！
Better hurry back!
ととっ…。
うわぁ！
いてぇ…。
Oww...
ギャーッ！
W-What is that?
な　な…　なんだ？
なんだよ！　岩か…。
Oh, it's a rock.
うん！？　なんだ？　これ…。
What is this?
札？
A tag?
Kisuke?
「奇介」…　あとは　読めねえな。
I can't make out the rest.
Oh no!
やべぇ！
は…　早く帰るってばよ。
I-I'd better get going.
サクラちゃん…。
Sakura...
S-Sakura... You're hugging me so hard.
サクラちゃん
そんな抱きつかなくって…。
サクラちゃん　ちょっと　重…。
Sakura... You're heavy.
ギャーッ！
な　な…　なんだよ！？　おっちゃん！
びっくりしたってばよ！！
Wh-Who are you, Mister?!
You gave me a scare!
I'm the one who's scared...
with you screaming out like that!
（奇介）こっちも　びっくりしたよ！
急に　大声出すから。
Hey Mister! You can't just
enter someone's home!
って…　おい　おっちゃん！　なんで
勝手に　人ん家に入ってんだよ！？
Huh?
うん！？　ううん…。
さぁ？　気づいたら　ここにいて…。
I don't know.
I came to, and here I was.
はぁ！？　なんだよ？　気づいたら
ここって　そんなバカな話…。
Huh?
What do you mean you "came to"?
That's ridiculous.
出た！！　オバケ！
（奇介）なに！？　どこ？　どこ？
A ghost!
What?! Where?!
どこにもいないじゃないか。
心臓に悪いだろ！
There's nothing there!
You're gonna give me
a heart attack!
おっちゃん…　それって…。
Mister... T-Take a look.
うん？
Huh?
そんな落ち込むなってばよぉ…。
Don't get too depressed.
つっても　無理か。
I guess it's hard not to.
So, Mister, you don't remember dying?
なあ　おっちゃん。
自分が死んだの　覚えてねえの？
そういえば…。
That's right!
What is it?
そういえば？
何も覚えてない。
I don't remember anything.
Wha-?
だあ～っ…。
っていうか
自分の名前も何も覚えてない。
In fact, I don't even remember
my name.
記憶喪失のオバケなんて
んなの聞いたことねえぞ！
I've never heard of a ghost
with amnesia!
俺もだよ。
君　何か　俺に祟られることした？
Same here.
Did you do something that
would make me haunt you?
んなことするわけねえってばよ！
Why would I?!
俺は　おっちゃんなんて
全然　知らねえし→
I don't even know you!
Why would I have
done something to you?!
祟られるようなことなんか
ちっと…。
- Wait!
- What?
あっ！
どうした？
Come to think of it,
last night...
そういえば　夕方…。
KISUKE
Back there in the hills
I peeled off a weird tag.
裏山で
変なお札を剥がしたなぁ。
Back there in the hills
I peeled off a weird tag.
お札？
ああ　ちょっと待って。
A tag?
Hold it!
それで　俺　化けて出てるの？
And that turned me into a ghost?
これだってばよ。
This is it!
奇介…　奇介ってのか？　俺。
Kisuke? Am I Kisuke?
そもそも　奇介とは名前なのか？
だとしたら　どこの奇介か？
Okay then, I guess Kisuke is my name.
But where am I from?
そんなの知らねえってばよ。
そうだよな…。
How would I know?
You're right.
But if I'm dead, why can't I just
rest in peace?
でも　死んだんなら
俺　なんで成仏できないんだ？
あっ！　この世に
なんか未練があるから→
I heard that ghosts remain in
the real world
成仏できねえって
聞いたことあるぞ。
because they have
lingering attachments.
Lingering...attachments, huh?
未練？　未練か…。
何の未練だろう？
I wonder what kind of attachments?
《う～ん…　これ
どうしたらいいんだってばよ》
What am I supposed to do with him?
- Leaf's History -
The Man Who Died Twice
((どうやら　おっちゃんが見えんの
俺だけみてぇだな。
Looks like I'm the only one
who can see you.
封印を解いた君だけに見えるのか。
So only you, who broke the seal,
can see me.
となると　君だけが頼りだな　ナルト。
That means you're the only one
I can rely on, Naruto.
ハア…　しようがねえ。
片っ端から聞いてみっか。
Then I guess I'll just have to go out
and ask around!
奇介？　知らないねぇ。
Kisuke? I don't know such a person.
聞いたことないなぁ。
Never heard of him.
知らないでちゅ。
I don't know him.
ニャーゴ。
ハア…　チェッ。
Sheesh.
誰も　おっちゃんのこと
知らねえってばよ。
No one knows you, Mister.
ダメか…。
あっ！　そうだ！
So it didn't work.
Hey, I know!
（イズモ）面会は無理だ。
三代目は　いらっしゃらない。
You can't see him.
The Third Hokage isn't in.
何かあったのか？
Did something happen?
重要な会議に出ておられる。
He's attending an important meeting.
ふ～ん
火影のじいちゃんなら→
I figured Old Man Hokage
would know something.
なんか知ってると
思ったんだけどな。
しゃあねえや。　他を当たるか。
Well then, guess I'll try someone else.
（サビル）ですから
この新たな警備網が→
With this new security network,
実現できれば　木ノ葉の防衛機能は
実に　３倍に飛躍します。
we'll be able to triple the strength
of the Hidden Leaf's defense system.
私としては　ぜひとも
この新たな防衛案に対する→
Personally, I believe this measure
is absolutely necessary,
ご理解を
皆様に求める次第であります。
and I recommend that you adopt it.
なるほどのう。
確かに　この案は名案じゃのう。
I see. Well, this is
an excellent plan indeed.
では　皆様
採決は午後ということで→
We will make the final decision
this afternoon.
休憩してください。
We'll take a recess now.
（サビル）コハル様　ホムラ様。
Lady Koharu! Lord Homura!
サビルか。
Oh, it's you, Sabiru.
（サビル）ご足労かけます。
いい案じゃった。
I appreciate your time today.
That was a good proposal.
お前も　ずいぶんと出世したな。
日頃の努力のたまものだ。
You've come up in the world.
It's a testament to your hard work.
ありがたき　お言葉。
Thank you for your kind words.
（サビル）私の生涯は
この里のためにあります。
My life is dedicated to this village.
（カカシ）あの若さで　里の新たな
防衛案を考えつくとは→
He's so young, yet he came up with
a new security plan for the village.
なかなかのものですね。
I'm very impressed.
（三代目）うむ。　午後の会議で→
If the measure is approved
during the afternoon session,
あの案が認可されれば
木ノ葉の平和は→
it will solidify the peace in
Hidden Leaf Village.
これまで以上に強固なものとなる。
やっぱ　ダメか…。
No luck.
はぁ…　俺の記憶は
戻らないのかなぁ。
Will I ever get my memory back?
そんな　しょんぼり
すんなってばよ。
Cheer up, Mister.
なっ　おっちゃん！
（サクラ）あっ　ナルト！
Hey, Naruto!
サクラちゃん！
アンタね　今日の演習　来ないで→
Sakura!
You missed today's exercises.
こんなところで
なに油売ってんのよ！
What are you dawdling around here for?!
あっ！　忘れてた！
忘れてた！　じゃないでしょ。
Oops, I completely forgot!
That's no excuse!
Oww...
痛い　痛い！　いや　それが→
No, I'm in a real pinch.
たいへんなことに
なってんだってばよ！
A real pinch?
たいへんなこと？
ほら　この…。
See! This...
Oh yeah, only I can see him.
あっ　俺以外には
見えねえんだった。
なに　わけわかんないこと
言ってんのよ！
You're not making any sense!
あんま　サボってると
先生に言いつけるわよ！
If you keep missing practice,
I'm going to tell on you to Sensei!
わかったってばよ。
ったく！
Okay, I hear you.
Jeez.
なんか　とばっちりだってばよ。
Cripes, what'd I get myself into?
すまないな　ナルト。
あっ　待ってよ　サクラちゃん！
I'm sorry, Naruto.
Hey, wait, Sakura!
なによ！
サクラちゃん　あのさ→
What?!
Do you know anyone named Kisuke
by any chance?
奇介って人　知らない？
奇介？　知らないわよ
そんな名前の人。
Kisuke?
I don't know anyone
by that name.
あっ！　そういえば
聞いたことあるかも。
Wait a second, I think I've heard
that name somewhere.
（２人）えっ！？
それって　どこで？
- What?!
- Where?!
う～ん　たしか…。
I think...
HIDDEN LEAF HOSPITAL
When I went to the hospital
to visit someone,
((知り合いのお見舞いで
病院に行ったときに→
the patient in
the very back room...
(奥の病室に入ってた人が…))
KISUKE MABOROSHI
あっ！
そんな…　俺じゃないか。
That's impossible.
That's me.
どうりで
成仏できねえはずだってばよ。
No wonder you can't
rest in peace, Mister.
まだ死んでねえんだもんな。
You're still alive.
(俺は　どうしてこんなとこに…))
What happened to me anyway?
((はぁ…。
おっちゃん　おっちゃん！
Mister... Mister!
ナルト。
Naruto...
おっちゃん家の住所
聞いてきたから→
I got your address,
so let's go over there.
行ってみるってばよ。
おっちゃん！
えっ？　ああ。
Mister!
Oh...okay.
ここが　俺の家。
This is my house?
チューリップ…。
A tulip.
おっちゃん家　だいぶ前に
火事になったらしい。
Your house burned down
quite a while ago.
そのとき…　言いづらいんだけど→
And I'm sorry to tell you this...
おっちゃんの奥さんも…。
but your wife died at the time.
おっちゃん？
Mister?
うわ～っ！　うぅ…。
おっちゃん　大丈夫か？
Mister! Are you all right?
ハァ…　ハァ…　ハァ…。
思い出した。
I remember now.
俺は　ヤツに…　うっ！
That guy, he...
封印されたんだ。
ヤツ？
sealed me away.
That guy?
俺は　暗部の命令で→
Under orders from Anbu Black Ops,
里に入り込んだ
スパイの捜索を続けていた。
I was investigating the infiltration
of spies in Hidden Leaf Village.
そこに　疑いが浮上してきたのが
サビルだった。
One man I came to suspect was Sabiru.
サビルは　都市防衛の戦術部門で
木ノ葉の未来を担うと→
Sabiru was an exceptional ninja in
the Tactical Division for Village Defense,
and it was thought that he would
guide the Hidden Leaf to its future.
ウワサされていた　優秀な忍だ。
確たる証拠もないのに
ヤツを糾弾することはできない。
I couldn't accuse him without
solid evidence.
それで俺は
誰にも　そのことを話さずに→
So I continued my investigation
without a word to anyone.
内偵を続けていた。
その最中…。
And then...
((出てこいよ。
Come on out.
俺が気づいてないと
思っているのか？
Or did you think I hadn't noticed?
何か勘づいてるようだが
かくれんぼもここまでだ。
It seems you're on to me,
but this cat-and-mouse game is over.
やはり　貴様！
So it is you!
逃がすか！
You won't get away!
何っ！？
Wha-?
これは！
What is this?!
終わりだ。
クソ！
It's over.
Damn it.
な～んてね。
Fooled you.
うわ～っ！
（サビル）たいしたことねぇな。
You're not that strong.
悪いが　ここに来る直前
お前の妻は始末させてもらった。
I hate to tell you this,
but I got rid of your wife
just before coming here.
なんだと！？
What did you say?!
Why you...
貴様！
ここで　お前の魂を封印すれば→
If I seal your soul here,
やがて　お前の肉体は
水死体で見つかるだろう。
you will probably be found
having drowned.
任務に疲れ　おかしくなったお前は
妻を道連れにし　川に身投げした。
Suffering from the stress
of your assignment,
you threw yourself and
your wife into the river.
一家心中という筋書きだ。
A husband-and-wife suicide.
That's the scenario.
じゃあな！
So long!
魂身別離の術！
Soul Detachment Jutsu.
(うっ…　うわ～っ！))
サビルの目的は→
Sabiru intends to put
his security network into place
自分の立てた防衛網を
木ノ葉にひくことだ。
in Hidden Leaf Village.
そうなれば→
Then he will have control of
the village's defense system.
ヤツが　里の守備機能の実権を
握ることになる。
それだけは
なんとしても阻止しなければ。
Whatever it takes,
he must be stopped.
But how?
でも　どうやって…。
先生　体温が。
血圧が上がりません。
Doctor, his temperature...
His blood pressure isn't going back up!
ダメです！
It's not working.
おっちゃん
どうしたんだってばよ。
Mister, what happened?!
下がって　治療の邪魔だ。
Step back, you're in our way!
Just what happened here?!
おい　いったい
何があったんだよ！
The life support system suddenly stopped.
それが　急に
生命維持装置がとまって…。
心拍　戻りません。
ダメか…。
I'm not getting a heart rate!
It's no use.
そんな…。
No way...
おっちゃん
死んじゃダメだってばよ！
Mister, you can't die!
おっちゃん…。
Mister...
泣くな　ナルト。
おっちゃん。
Don't cry, Naruto!
Mister!
誰かが装置をとめて
俺を殺したんだ。
Someone turned off my life support
and killed me.
What?
犯人は　俺の存在が邪魔なヤツ。
The culprit is someone who
found me to be a threat.
サビルか！
You mean, Sabiru?
これより　サビルの提案による→
And now, we will vote on
Sabiru's security network measure
for the Hidden Leaf Village.
木ノ葉防衛網議案の
可決に移ります。
では
本議案に賛成の者は挙手を。
All those in favor of this plan,
raise your hands!
ふむ。　では　本案は
賛成多数をもって可決…。
By majority vote to adopt this measure-
異議あり！
I oppose!
その決議　待ってください！
Please wait on your decision!
- Who are you?
- Kisuke?
お前は…。
奇介！？
What do you mean you oppose?
異議というのは
どういうことかね？
私は　暗部の奇介という者です。
My name is Kisuke and I belong
to the Anbu Black Ops.
特命を受け
密かにこの里に潜入した→
I was on a secret mission to
investigate a spy
スパイの捜査をしていました。
who had infiltrated our village.
それが　この議決と
何の関係があるのかね？
And what does that have to do
with today's resolution?
A whole lot, I tell you!
おおありだってばよ。
ナルト　興奮するな。
変化の術がバレる。
Naruto, don't get too excited or
they'll see through your Transformation Jutsu.
わかったってばよ。
I know that.
おおありじゃなくて
大いに関係があります。
What I meant was,
it has much to do with it.
Because the one under investigation
happens to be Sabiru!
なぜなら　私が捜査していたのは
そこにいる　サビルなのですから。
なんだと！？
なに！
- What?
- Impossible!
One moment please!
お待ちください。
では　奇介
その証拠は　どこにある？
Well then, Kisuke, where is the proof?!
私は　お前に魂を封印された。
You sealed away my soul!
私自身が証拠だ。
This very body is the proof!
それは　お前が本当の奇介ならな。
That's...if you're the real Kisuke.
奇介は　先ほど死亡したと
報告を受けた。　確認を！
I received a report that
Kisuke died a while earlier.
Verify this!
Yes sir.
クッ…　ここまでか。
Is this the end?
Damn it!
クソ！
What?
《なに！？》
This Kisuke is an imposter!
この奇介は　ニセモノだ　捕らえろ！
Arrest him!
チッ　見失ったか。
I've lost sight of him.
お前は　いったい誰だ？
Just who are you?!
そんな姿で俺の前に
現れるってことは　奇介の仲間か？
Appearing before me like that...
Are you helping Kisuke?
悪いが　お前にも死んでもらうぜ。
That's unfortunate because
you're going to die too.
やっぱり　お前が　おっちゃんと
奥さんを殺したんだな。
So you did kill him
and his wife, after all.
誰だ　小僧。
Who are you, brat?
そうなんだな？
だとしたら？
Isn't that so?
And if I did?
許せねえ。
You won't get away with it!
すべて　ナルトの言うとおりだったな。
You were right about everything, Naruto.
解！
Release!
カカシ。
Kakashi?!
He happens to be one
of my subordina
ま　一応
ソイツは俺の大事な部下なんでね。
木ノ葉の防衛網の実権を握り→
何をするつもりだったのか
詳しく話してもらうよ。
覚悟しろ　サビル。
待ってくれ　カカシ先生！
おっちゃん
自分で仇を討つってばよ。
ああ！
（２人）変化の術！
サビル覚悟しろ。　多重影分身の術！
いくぞ！
サビル　食らえ！
うわ～っ！
なに？
おい！
チッ。
ダメだ　カカシ先生。
《消されたか》
ありがとう　ナルト。
キミのおかげで里は救われたよ。
俺じゃねえ。
おっちゃんが取り憑いてくれた
おかげだってばよ。
そんなことはないさ。
けど　おっちゃん…。
ホントにお化けになっちまって。
いいんだよ。　あの世で
妻を見つけて　幸せに暮らすさ。
ナルト　ひとつ頼みがあるんだが。
何だってばよ。
もし　俺を
思い出すことがあったら→
俺たちの墓に
チューリップを飾ってくれないか？
妻が大好きだったんだ。
ああ。
じゃあな　ナルト。　お別れだ。
俺たちのぶんまで生きろよ。
おっちゃん！
ああ　奇介のおっちゃん！
(じゃあな！))